<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>deep learning on My Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in deep learning on My Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fingerprint Verification System</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/fingerprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/fingerprint/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT REPORT: FINGERPRINT VERIFICATION SYSTEM Led a team of six data scientists and engineers to design and implement a highly secure biometric user authentication system using Neural Fuzzy Extractor (NFE) and Artificial Neural Networks (ANN), achieving a marginal improvement in the equal error rate (EER) from 5.75% to 5.82%, while ensuring minimal loss of FVC2006 fingerprint data. Enhanced the precision of the fingerprint data by formulating a robust deep learning algorithm, specifically a Siamese Network with a triplet loss function, resulting in an Area Under Curve (AUC) score of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Biometric Authenticator Using Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/blogs/blog-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/blogs/blog-5/</guid>
      <description>What is biometric authentication? Biometric authentication is a mode of verifying a user based on some part of their physical features. Authentication is different from identification, where biometrics such as fingerprint, face, retina scan, etc. are used to identify a person. In authentication, biometrics are used to verify if a user is what they are claiming to be.
Importance of biometric authenticator This is one of the most popular forms of security when it comes to digital identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Pointer Controller</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/computer_pointer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/computer_pointer/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT REPORT: COMPUTER POINTER CONTROLLER Computer Pointer Controller app is built using Intel OpenVINO toolkit. This app is used to control mouse pointer using our eye and head movement. We can use a recorded video stream or a webcam directly for the input.
Project Set Up and Installation To do this project, we need to first download the OpenVINO toolkit in our local machine. Instructions can be found here.
To activate the environment open command prompt in windows then:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People Counter App</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/people_counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/people_counter/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT REPPORT: PEOPLE COUNTER APP Programming Language: Python 3.5 or 3.6 What it Does The people counter application will demonstrate how to create a smart video IoT solution using Intel® hardware and software tools. The app will detect people in a designated area, providing the number of people in the frame, average duration of people in frame, and total count.
How it Works The counter will use the Inference Engine included in the Intel® Distribution of OpenVINO™ Toolkit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/skills/dl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/skills/dl/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning:
Proficient in PyTorch and Keras, I specialize in developing and fine-tuning deep learning models for tasks such as image classification, natural language processing, and computer vision.
Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN) Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) Transfer Learning Autoencoders Necessary DL Tools:
Pandas: A data manipulation library that provides easy-to-use data structures and data analysis tools. NumPy: A powerful library for numerical computing in Python, providing support for large, multi-dimensional arrays and mathematical functions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
