<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recommendation on My Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/tags/recommendation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recommendation on My Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/tags/recommendation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Movie Recommendation System</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/movie_reco/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/movie_reco/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT REPORT: MOVIE RECOMMENDATION SYSTEM CONCEPT The Movie Recommendation System project aims to develop a movie recommendation system that suggests movies to users based on their preferences. The objective is to provide personalized movie recommendations using various recommendation methods, including content-based filtering (most popular movies), collaborative filtering, and user-specific recommendations.
DATA The movie data for this project is gathered from the following sources:
MovieLens: 27,000,000 ratings and 1,100,000 tag applications applied to 58,000 movies by 280,000 users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Spending Pojections at Starbucks</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/strabucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/strabucks/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT REPORT: CUSTOMER SPENDING PROJECTIONS AT STARBUCKS CONCEPT
The Customer Spending Projections at Starbucks project aimed to analyze Starbucks&amp;rsquo; sales data to understand customer spending patterns and provide insights for offering personalized coupons and recommendations. The project leveraged a dataset consisting of customer profiles, promotional offers, and transaction logs to gain insights into purchase decisions and offer influence.
DATASET OVERVIEW
The dataset comprised three files: profile.json, portfolio.json, and transcript.json. The profile file contained information about rewards program users, including gender, age, income, and membership details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Recommendation System</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/book_reco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/projects/book_reco/</guid>
      <description>PROJECT REPORT: BOOK RECOMMENDATION SYSTEM CONCEPT The Book Recommendation System project aims to develop a book recommendation system that suggests books to users based on their preferences. The objective is to provide personalized book recommendations using collaborative filtering.
DATA The book data for this project is gathered from the following sources:
Goodreads API: An API that provides access to book data, including book titles, authors, genres, ratings, and reviews. APPROACH The project utilizes the following workflows to generate book recommendations:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
