<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on My Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on My Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secure architecture for biometric authentication</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub3/</guid>
      <description>Inventors: George T Amariucai, Pascal Hitzler, Abhishek Jana, Monireh Ebrahimi, Md Kamruzzaman Sarker
Patent office: US
Year: 2023
Link: Link to Patent
Abstract: Computer-implemented methods, systems and computer-readable media for building and using an artificial intelligence model for secure biometric authentication. Utilizing difference vectors, the model securely relates output vectors generated from noisy biometric data of a plurality of enrolled users to pre-defined fixed points in a vector space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constraining Galaxy Halo Connection Using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub2/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Abhishek Jana, Lado Samushia
Conference/Journal: American Astronomical Society Meeting Abstracts
Year: 2023
Link: Link to Publication
Abstract: We investigate the possibility of modeling various measures of small-scale galaxy clustering with machine learning methods to constrain parameters of the halo occupation distribution (HOD) model. Using ML techniques results in faster Markov Chain Monte Carlo convergence (within minutes). We find that great care must be taken when using machine learning algorithms in this regime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural fuzzy extractors: A secure way to use artificial neural networks for biometric user authentication</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub1/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Abhishek Jana, Md Kamruzzaman Sarker, Monireh Ebrahimi, Pascal Hitzler, George T Amariucai
Year: 2022
Conference/Journal: Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies, 4, 86-104.
Link: Link to Publication
Abstract: In this paper, we introduce a secure way to handle user-specific information involved with the use of artificial neural networks for biometric authentication. Our proposed architecture, called a Neural Fuzzy Extractor (NFE), allows the coupling of pre-existing classifiers with fuzzy extractors, through an artificial-neuralnetwork-based buffer called an expander, with minimal or no performance degradation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possibilities of Present Day Acceleration Using Double Scalar Field</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub5/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Abhishek Jana
Conference/Journal: Indian Institute of Science Education and Research Kolkata
Year: 2016
Link: Link to Publication
Abstract: The present work deals with a dark energy model with two scalar fields. Such a model has been proved to be successful in providing a model for in ation in the early universe. With two scalar fields, one has a better handle on the model parameters. The ultimate motivation is to use this freedom to construct a model which can drive acceleration both at early and the late time acceleration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ScalPy: A Python Package For Late Time Scalar Field Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhishek-jana.github.io/aiwithabhi/publications/pub4/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Sumit Kumar, Abhishek Jana, Anjan A Sen
Conference/Journal: arXiv preprint arXiv:1503.02407
Year: 2015
Link: Link to Publication
Abstract: We present a python package &amp;ldquo;ScalPy&amp;rdquo; for studying the late time scalar field cosmology for a wide variety of scalar field models, namely the quintessence, tachyon and Galileon model. The package solves the autonomous system of equations for power law and exponential potential. But it can be easily generalized to add more complicated potential.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
